Guide to the Department of Classical Studies Records, 1925-2018 UA.25.13.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Department of Classical Studies records
1925-2018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Department of Classical Studies
UA.25.13.0001
6.0 Linear Feet
9.5 Gigabytes
Originally the classical studies curriculum was spread over two separate departments which were Latin and Roman studies, and Greek studies. In 1962, these disciplines combined to become Classical Studies. This collection contains materials related to the Department of Classical Studies including minutes, materials created by students in classical studies classes, correspondence, financial records, a course paper, flyers, and other materials.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note: Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Provenance
The Department of Classical Studies Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer starting in 1968.
Historical Note
The Classical Studies department seeks to provide students with a broad background in the disciplines of the field. Originally the classical studies curriculum was spread over two separate departments which were Latin and Roman studies, and Greek studies. In 1962, these disciplines combined to become Classical Studies.
Collection Overview
This collection contains materials related to the Department of Classical Studies including minutes, correspondence, financial records, a course paper, flyers, and other materials. Materials created during classical studies courses are also included in the collection. For example, CS95, Introduction to Archoaeology, in the fall of 1992 (Professor John Younger) had students excavate an area on East Campus that had been the site of Trinity College's faculty housing. The course paper titled "Faculty Row, A Detailed History of the Homes along Trinity College's Faculty Avenue, 1992" is included in the collection. This collection also contains the records (1927-1965) of the Greek Department.
Also included are graduate instructor materials from the 2010s, including syllabi, past exams, and course information, which was formerly available in the Classical Studies library. In addition, there are other administrative and departmental materials including: forms, policies, newsletters, photographs of staff and students, slides for courses, and other materials.
Duke University. Dept. of Classical Studies; Duke University. Greek Department; Machine-readable artifacts; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Buildings
- Container List, 1925-1993, 5.3 Linear Feet; 6 boxes, 1 oversize folder
  Scope and Contents note
  General files listed below include miscellaneous correspondence, memos, clippings, and other printed material. Please note that administrative records are restricted for 25 years from date of origin; contact research services for more information.
  - Department of Classical Studies General Files, 1977-1980 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Classics Review Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Classics Review Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1973-1974, Dean Joerg (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1974-1975, Dean Lewis (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1975-1976, Dean Lewis (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1976-1977, Dean Lewis (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1976-1977, Dean Joerg (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Classical Studies, Dept. of. Records, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Classical Studies Department, 1930-1977 (Box 1)
  - Classical Studies, Flyers 1969-1980 (Box 1)
  - Department of Classical Studies General Files, 1969-1975 (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Departmental Evaluation, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Department of Classical Studies General Files, 1975-1977 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1935-1936 (Box 3)
  - Archeological Institute of America, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Applications, 1935-1942 (Box 3)
  - American School of Classical Study at Athens, 1927-1960 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bibliography (Box 3)
  - Books for the Library, 1934-1937 (Box 3)
  - Miss Catherine Bradshaw, 1940, 1942, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Class Census Reports, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
  - Herbert L. Cain, 1937-1942 (Box 3)
  - Classical Club of Duke University, 1925-1933 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Duke Council for American Defense, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
  - Undergraduate Examinations, 1936 (Box 4)
  - President W.P. Few, 1936-1940 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - Dean W.K. Greene, 1935-1941 (Box 4)
  - Graduate School Office, 1932-1944 (Box 4)
  - Dean H.J. Herring, 1936, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Virginia Holder, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Matters, 1935-1942, undated (Box 4)
  - Honors in Greek, 1935-1938 (Box 5)
  - P.C. Lamas, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Latin Songs, undated (Box 5)
  - Lectures, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - C.C. Jernigan, 1932, 1940, undated (Box 5)
  - Charles B. Markham, 1937-1941 (Box 5)
  - H.W. Miller, 1931-1943 (Box 5)
  - Library, 1935-1944 (Box 5)
  - N.Y.A., 1935-1942 (Box 5)
  - Dean Manchester, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Paintings on slides, 1933, undated (Box 5)
  - Miss Enid Parker, 1934, undated (Box 5)
  - Periodicals for the Library, 1927-1939 (Box 5)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 5)
  - Philosophy department (Box 5)
  - Henry S. Robinson, 1938-1942 (Box 5)
  - Research Council, 1935-1941, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Mrs. Frances Craghead Schaedler, 1943 (Box 5)
  - M.L. Stirewalt, 1934-1942 (Box 5)
  - Miss Anne Turner, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Undergraduate College, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
  - Woman's College of Duke University, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Frederick Wood, 1938-1940 (Box 5)
  - Wong, David. Faculty Row: A detailed history of the homes along Trinity College's Faculty Avenue, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Plans, elevations, detailed drawings, and mathematical analyses of Baldwin Auditorium done by students as examples of Greek Revival and Greek influenced architecture, circa 1992-1993 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession UA2018.0082
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes Graduate Instructor information, including past exams, syllabi, guidelines, and course information. This material was publicly accessible from the Classical Studies department library and is not subject to an administrative restriction.
  - Past Graduate Preliminary and Language Exams, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Graduate Instructor Course Information: Graduate Guidelines (Box 6)
  - Graduate Instructor Course Information, 4 folders (Box 6)
- Accession UA2018.0087
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access note: Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Art of Hell photographs, 2007-2008; 113 files; 2.41 GB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Photographs of slides for class. Files are predominately in TIF format.
  - Classical Studies (CLST) Newsletter, 2014-2017; 142 files; 50 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Weekly departmental newsletter that includes important news, information, and events. Files are in PDF and DOC formats.
  - Classical Studies courses, 2015-2018; 148 files; 37 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Includes syllabi and flyers. Files are in PDF, DOC, RTF, and TXT formats.
  - CLST Library, 1993-2018; 91 files; 57 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Files relating to the Classical Studies library, including inventories, information about donations, and other files. Files are predominately in XLS, FP7 (FileMaker Pro), PDF, and DOC formats.
  - Department photographs, 1991-2015; 534 files; 1.4 GB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Photographs of faculty and events; includes photographs from studying abroad, a papyrology project, and graduation along with other events. Files are predominately in JPG format.
  - Events and Speakers, 1995-2020; 502 files; 194 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Correspondence, publicity, and logistical and adminstrative files about events hosted by the department. Includes files that are predominately in PDF, DOC, PPT, PNG, JPG formats.
  - Forms, Instructions, Policies, 2004-2017; 64 files; 5.6 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Files in DOC, PDF, XLS, and JPG formats.
  - LUNA database project, 2004-2007; 46 files; 67 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Files relating to a database project for departmental slides. Files in TXT, FP7 (FileMaker Pro), JPG, DOC, and other formats.
  - Miscellaneous administrative materials, 506 files; 153 MB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Templates, calendars, listserv information, email addresses, how-to guides, a promotional video, and other documents related to the day-to-day administration of the department. Files primarily in DOC, PDF, XLS, PPT, JPG, PNG, MP4, and GIF formats.
  - PHEME Newsletter, 2006-2018; 1,385 files; 5.1 GB (Digital-materials UA25130001-SET-0001)
    Files predominantely in DOC, PDF, JPG, TIF, PMD, and XLS formats.
- Accession UA2019.0065
  - PHEME Newsletter, 1995-2017; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Classical Studies Publications/Handbooks, 1990; 2016-2017 (Box 6)
  - Duke Publications (Box 6)
  - Richardson Conference, October 1990 (Box 6)
  - Resolution for Joint Duke/UNC: German Studies, 2007 (Box 6)
    Administrative restriction until 2032.